<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Social impact &#8211; Outsprint</title>
	<atom:link href="/skill/social-impact/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>The fastest way to innovate public policy &#38; social services.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 08:28:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/cropped-logo-square-rounded-corner-e1517212607710-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Social impact &#8211; Outsprint</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Outsprint Store: Design tools for public good</title>
		<link>/portfolio/outsprint-store/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[jason]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 16:23:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=portfolio&#038;p=610</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>At Outsprint, we believe in the power of human-centered design for creating public good and social impact. Having done many projects with government agencies and non-profit organisations, we developed many tools along the way. Tools to help us shed light on public and social issues around employment, technology, government-citizen relationships, and more. Tools that others [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/portfolio/outsprint-store/">Outsprint Store: Design tools for public good</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Outsprint</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<section class="stag-section stag-intro-text"><p>Outsprint Store: Design tools for public good</p>
</section>
<p>At Outsprint, we believe in the power of human-centered design for creating public good and social impact. Having done many projects with government agencies and non-profit organisations, we developed many tools along the way. Tools to help us shed light on public and social issues around employment, technology, government-citizen relationships, and more. Tools that others have asked us to share. We thought, “Why let these tools go to waste, after a project is done?” So here they are. Check out the <a href="https://store.outsprint.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">store</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/portfolio/outsprint-store/">Outsprint Store: Design tools for public good</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Outsprint</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Innovating grant-making with SG Enable</title>
		<link>/portfolio/grant-experience-design-sg-enable/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[jason]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2015 23:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=portfolio&#038;p=325</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>To learn more about the grant experience design project, including all about the design sprint process during the project and its final design recommendations, read the blog post series 1, 2, and 3. The project deliverable can be downloaded here.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/portfolio/grant-experience-design-sg-enable/">Innovating grant-making with SG Enable</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Outsprint</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<section class="stag-section stag-intro-text"><p>Designing a new end-to-end grant experience with SG Enable, from ground up, from outside in.</p>
</section>
<p><div class="stag-column stag-one-half">The Tote Board Enabling Lives Initiative (TB-ELI) Grant is a new grant that aims to create meaningful social impact for persons with disabilities and their caregivers. The grant is open to Voluntary Welfare Organizations (VWOs), non-profit organizations, social enterprises, and private corporations with a social mission. Besides pilot projects, the grant will also fund existing programmes that need resources to scale up.</p>
<p>With an all-new grant, the SG Enable TB-ELI Programme Office had the exciting opportunity to envision a new way of grant-making. SG Enable approached Outsprint to tap on human-centred design to explore new areas for redesign of the end-to-end experience of the entire grant process. The team felt duty-bound to challenge the status quo, but only if the status quo was a worse-off future than our vision for the grant experience.</div><div class="stag-column stag-one-half stag-column-last">We asked what do we want the grantees to feel at the end of their grant?</p>
<h4><em>What if a grant wasn’t just about the money? How might we create a holistic experience around the grant, that supports and excites an entire sector?</em></h4>
<p>What’s the current relationship like between grant applicants and fund administrators? How does collaboration happen? What does the sector need most and how would the grant add unique value? How do we create new ways of solving old problems? It was in the spirit of these big questions that we started a design sprint project to learn more and design better.</div><div class="clear"></div></p>
<hr class="stag-section stag-divider stag-divider--plain">
<p>To learn more about the grant experience design project, including all about the design sprint process during the project and its final design recommendations, read the blog post series <a title="Designing an end-to-end experience for grants - Outsprint blog" href="/4/designing-an-end-to-end-experience-for-grants/">1</a>, <a title="8 human insights into the grant experience - Outsprint blog" href="/420/8-human-insights-into-the-grant-experience/">2</a>, and <a title="The ideal grant experience - Outsprint blog" href="/425/the-ideal-grant-experience/">3</a>. The project deliverable can be downloaded <a title="Download report here" href="https://outsprint.typeform.com/to/N5MBFc" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/portfolio/grant-experience-design-sg-enable/">Innovating grant-making with SG Enable</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Outsprint</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: http://www.w3-edge.com/wordpress-plugins/

Page Caching using disk: enhanced
Database Caching using disk
Object Caching 1025/1100 objects using disk
Content Delivery Network via N/A

 Served from: outsprint.io @ 2021-01-05 21:26:56 by W3 Total Cache -->