<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Biography &#8211; Outsprint</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/biography/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>The fastest way to innovate public policy &#38; social services.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2015 16:21:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/cropped-logo-square-rounded-corner-e1517212607710-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Biography &#8211; Outsprint</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>First, an introduction</title>
		<link>/266/intro/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[jason]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2015 18:04:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Random]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Credentials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Team]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=266</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Jason’s first forays in design was helping businesses build online brands through user-centered web design, as well as applying design thinking to developing his freelance business. Before starting out as a designer, he was previously with the National Council of Social Service where he helped develop new social services and championed ground-up collaboration between government [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/266/intro/">First, an introduction</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Outsprint</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jason’s first forays in design was helping businesses build online brands through user-centered web design, as well as applying design thinking to developing his freelance business. Before starting out as a designer, he was previously with the <a title="National Council of Social Service" href="http://www.ncss.gov.sg/" target="_blank">National Council of Social Service</a> where he helped develop new social services and championed ground-up collaboration between government agencies, voluntary welfare organisations and the grassroots.</p>
<p>At <a title="The He(Art) Of Designing Policies | Challenge magazine" href="http://www.challenge.gov.sg/print/feature/the-he%28art%29-of-designing-policies" target="_blank">The Human Experience Lab</a> in the <a title="Public Service Diviion, Prime Minister's Office" href="http://www.psd.gov.sg/" target="_blank">Public Service Division</a>, Jason had the opportunity to bring his passions for human-centered design, social innovation and entrepreneurship into government to create public good. He spent 2 months working as part of the design consultancy team at the globally renowned innovation firm <a title="IDEO" href="http://www.ideo.com/" target="_blank">IDEO</a>, on a project commissioned by the housing authorities and PSD to look into the future narrative of public housing in Singapore. He led 7 multi-agency projects, interviewing more than 70 people (in one-to-one or group settings) on wide variety of public and social issues such as public housing, neighbourliness, career aspirations, life aspirations, financial literacy, employment for persons with disabilities, and community inclusiveness. The job also required teaching and facilitating some 15 training workshops on design thinking, as well as guiding the artistic and editorial style, copywriting and visual communication for project collateral such as videos, print reports, and posters. The Ministries and Statutory Boards he had worked with and consulted for includes SG Enable, MSF, NCSS, MOE, MTI, MND, MOF, HDB, PA, CSCDC, PSD, NHGP, EMA, STB, HPB, CSC and even public officers from the <a title="CAPAM conference" href="http://www.newsarawaktribune.com/news/13782/CAPAM-Meeting-and-Forum-to-be-held-in-Kuching/" target="_blank">Commonwealth</a> countries such as Malaysia.</p>
<p>He is now running <a title="Design sprints for public good &amp; social impact." href="/" target="_blank">Outsprint</a>, a social enterprise as public innovation design consultancy, creating products and services that deliver public good and social impact. He recently helped <a title="SG Enable" href="https://www.sgenable.sg/" target="_blank">SG Enable</a>, an agency dedicated to enabling persons with disability, design a new end-to-end grant experience through a one-week design sprint.</p>
<p>His voracious reading and passion for sharing online articles had now found some popularity and practical use, in the <a title="Design For Public Good Flipboard magazine" href="http://flip.it/CAG40" target="_blank">Design For Public Good Flipboard magazine</a>, with over 11,000 followers.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/266/intro/">First, an introduction</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Outsprint</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: http://www.w3-edge.com/wordpress-plugins/

Page Caching using disk: enhanced
Database Caching using disk
Object Caching 945/1031 objects using disk
Content Delivery Network via N/A

 Served from: outsprint.io @ 2021-01-05 21:27:09 by W3 Total Cache -->